<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bevan Philip</title>
    <link>https://bphilip.uk/tags/video-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content Bevan Philip</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bphilip.uk/tags/video-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kernel-level anti-cheats: a necessary devil</title>
      <link>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2024-07-29-evaluating-kernel-level-anti-cheats-as-a-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2024-07-29-evaluating-kernel-level-anti-cheats-as-a-consumer/</guid>
      <description>Cheating is an increasingly endemic problem to multiplayer video games on PCs, and as a response, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen the &amp;ldquo;Cambrian explosion&amp;rdquo; of anti-cheats designed to combat this situation.
However, a vast majority of these products are choosing to run with the highest privileges possible on your system: the kernel-level. This choice has caused a lot of scrutiny from customers over the possible ramifications of this decision on their usage of their computer: particularly, over the privacy, security and stability of their PCs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Will Counter-Strike coaching evolve?</title>
      <link>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2024-07-14-will-cs-coaching-evolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2024-07-14-will-cs-coaching-evolve/</guid>
      <description>Recently, CS professionals STYKO and EliGE have shared the fact that they have employed the services of aim coaches. Such moves are relatively new to Counter-Strike: while aiming is considered an important aspect to Counter-Strike, professionals usually improve their skill in this venture with deathmatching, or training with Counter-Strike maps such as &amp;ldquo;aim_botz&amp;rdquo;, or full bespoke suites such as Refrag (EliGE partly owns Refrag, after acquiring it from ESEA).
CS, as is typical, is late to the party.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need more online CS</title>
      <link>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-11-06-we-need-more-online-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-11-06-we-need-more-online-cs/</guid>
      <description>The mundanity of seeing online CS during the pandemic has electrified a transition that was already happening - the end of tier 1 online events. The leagues were the last victims, with FLASHPOINT&amp;rsquo;s last event setting the framework for future online events.
But the pandemic also unearthed a deeper scar tissue within the scene - the economics stopped making sense a long time ago. The industry has tried to paper over this with agreements such as the Louvre Agreement - tournament organisers would sell a fixed number of slots, which would guarantee you access to tier 1 offline events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NA CS is dead, but maybe it was always going to be</title>
      <link>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-09-12-na-cs-is-dead-but-maybe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-09-12-na-cs-is-dead-but-maybe/</guid>
      <description>North American Counter-Strike is dead, or in the middle of dying.
Team Liquid, the prototypical NA team, now fields a primarily European roster, while Cloud9&amp;rsquo;s roster is Russian. The remaining stalwarts in Complexity and EG are not competitive internationally.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t unique to North America. This death of the national team is framed as a problem endemic to North America. But one only needs to look in Europe to see that the concept as a whole, is withering away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Makes a CS:GO Major Playoff Stand Out?</title>
      <link>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-05-30-what-makes-a-major-standout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-05-30-what-makes-a-major-standout/</guid>
      <description>CS:GO Majors are supposed to be a raucous celebration of the game. The place where the best teams duke it out, in a desperate bid to establish themselves as the apex predator. There is no such as a free round within this theatre.
Yet Boston 2018 was the last CS:GO major final to ever reach 3 maps.
7 consecutive major finals, where the loser could not muster one map.
What is going on?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have CS rounds gotten slower?</title>
      <link>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-04-26-have-cs-rounds-gotten-slower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bphilip.uk/blog/2023-04-26-have-cs-rounds-gotten-slower/</guid>
      <description>Counter-Strike events seem to have less energy than ever. There are no concrete statistics to back this up, but the symphonies of Counter-Strike sound more like a small chorale. The crowds have gone from ecstasy, to gentle applause.
If this is the case, pointing to a single cause is difficult. To list a few changes:
The makeup of teams has changed, with fan favourites such as NiP, SK and fnatic having all disappeared from the high levels of the scene.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
